Beatriz MEYTHALER

UX designer with a background in law and 7 years of experience driving business growth and building strong brand awareness through customer-centric digital strategies. Holds an MBA and a certification in User Experience Design. Known for his proactive approach and intellectual curiosity. Passionate about creating practical, engaging and easy-to-use solutions.

Berlin, Germany +49 176 6601 0123 beatrizmeythalerg@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin</u> <u>Portfolio website</u>

UX PROJECTS

Untangled, Legal App for Entrepreneurs — 2023

Final Project for UX Design Immersion Course: CareerFoundry

Designed a legal app for entrepreneurs ensuring reliable, fast, and affordable protection of their interests and businesses. Link to project.

Tools: Figma, Miro, Trello, Canva, Optimal Workshop, Helio and Survey Monkey.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Innovation & Legal Marketing Lead, Meythaler & Zambrano LawFirm - Quito, Ecuador (Part-time)

lune 2023 - Present

- Conducted market research to identify lucrative business opportunities, expanding the client base with approximately.
- Produced SEO-optimized content for a legal blog with 3,000+ subscribers, driving consistent monthly LinkedIn follower growth of 200.
- Developed targeted business proposals based on market analysis, attracting potential clients in areas such as Data Protection.
- Implemented digital solutions to streamline legal operations and enhance client service efficiency.
- Managed submissions to legal directories, showcasing the firm's digital expertise and achievements.

Business Development and Legal Marketing Consultant, Gericó Associates - Madrid, Spain (Full time - Remote)

May 2022 - June 2023

- Conducted qualitative and quantitative analyses of legal firms, supporting strategic positioning and identifying emerging legal trends.
- As an Account Manager, I assisted 44 law firm accounts in submitting to the
 most respected legal directories, as part of a business development and
 expansion initiative, handling a total of 178 submissions throughout the
 vear.
- Retention of 2 initially dissatisfied accounts as new Key Account Manager, resulted in the clients extending the contract for another year due to

SKILLS

Advanced Market Research
Detailed Competitive Analysis
Usability Testing
SEO Content Creation
Legal Directories
User Experience Design
Responsive Web Design
UX Research
Front-End Design
(HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

TOOLS

Figma

Git and Github

Google Analytics

Marvel

Miro

Semrush

Trello

Visual Studio Code

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent)
Spanish (Native)
German (Intermediate)

improved performance.

SEO Content Marketing Creator, Lumiform - Berlin, Germany (Full time)

August 2021 - February 2022

- Collaborated on website user experience improvements, applying usability testing and competitive analysis to increase organic traffic.
- Produced daily SEO articles, generating B2B and B2C leads, resulting in substantial organic traffic growth that outperformed other language versions and attracted more Spanish-speaking clients.
- Collaborated with UX designers and SEO managers to enhance the Spanish website, improving the user experience.
- Conducted audits to identify and improve culturally sensitive and language-proficient content, aiming to boost organic traffic.

MBA Project Consultant, Leaf Labs - Berlin, Germany

October 2020 - December 2020

- Conducted market research to identify potential markets for international expansion.
- Formulated and validated hypotheses through qualitative surveys.
- Provided customer-centric recommendations for market entry.
- A/B testing to enhance the website's user experience and conversion rates.

Digital Strategy and Legal Operations Manager, Meythaler & Zambrano LawFirm - Quito, Ecuador

January 2017 - December 2019

- Implemented a digital strategy, creating a website and managing social media, resulting in about 250 new contracts.
- Collaborated on a web application to improve lawyer performance analysis, resulting in a remarkable **55% increase** over the next 2 years.
- Analyzed attorney performance and efficiently organized daily administrative operations, ensuring the delivery of legal services to the entire client portfolio. E.g. Led a team of 38 staff members, providing guidance to legal interns and deputy chiefs.

Inhouse Lawyer, GlaxoSmithKline Ecuador S.A.

January 2017 - December 2019

- Mitigated regulatory and contractual risks in 50+ transactions up to US \$2.5 million.
- Aligned GSK's global contractual guidelines with Ecuadorian regulations and oversaw transactions across **5 departments**.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry, Berlin -Germany

2022 - 2023

UX Design with Frontend Specialization.

European School of Management, Berlin -Germany

2020 - 2021

Master of Business Administration

Specialization in Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management. Project Consultant for <u>Leaf' international expansion</u>.

Universidad San Francisco de Quito, Ecuador

(2011 - 2016)

Bachelor of Laws

Specialization in Environmental Law. Graduated with honors: Cum Laude.

Author of the Book "The Need of direct data protection of biological medicine in Ecuador" (2016) published by Center of studies for development of pharmaceutical industry in Argentina.